Nithish Kumar Megarajan

4/3 70 Miller Street, Glasgow, United Kingdom, G1 1DT

nithishmegaraj05@gmail.com

07949162396

nithishk.com

Due to graduate in 2023, I Have gained technical knowledge from my course and by doing some simple projects on my own. Used various programming languages, operating system, and development tools to update myself with the current computing environment. Specialising in Java and JavaScript, I am keen to develop my skills by getting an intern in software development.

Education

University of Strathclyde (2019 – Present)

Glasgow, United Kingdom.

BSc Software Engineering with industrial year.

Predicted First Class Honours.

Direct Entrant to Year 2 of the Degree.

University of Strathclyde International Study Centre (2018 – 2019)

Glasgow, United Kingdom.

Achieved 78% in Computing 1.

Achieved 93% in Computing 2.

The Velammal International School (CBSE) (2016-2018)

Chennai, India.

63 % in my Second Final School exams which include subjects English, Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Science.

95 % in my first year Final School exams which include subjects English, Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Computer Science.

SRI VIJAY VIDYASHRAM SCHOOL (CBSE) (2010-2016)

Chennai, India

9 CGPA In my Final exam's subjects include English, Maths, Physics, Chemistry, Biology, Tamil.

IT Skills

- Development tools: MATLAB and ModelSim Packages: MS Office and Photoshop.
- Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, php, Haskell, C++, and C#.
- Programming Tools: Git, IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code and NPM.
- Database Management: MongoDB.
- Frameworks & Libraries: node.js, socket.io and express.
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, and SASS.
- Operating Systems: Android, iOS, Mac, Windows, and Linux.

Other Skills

- Participated and progressed till the last stage in World Robo Olympiad held in Singapore.
- Won many state awards in Unirobo Olympiad held in India.
- Certified as Microsoft Office specialist by Microsoft.

Work experience

- Rishi's Indian Aroma (Glasgow) as a part time waiter (2019 2021)
- Chaophraya (Glasgow) as a Bartender (2021-2022)

Positions of Responsibility (2014-2015)

Assistant School Pupil leader.

- Conducted regular meetings to discuss assignments and deadlines.
- Had good feedback when results out.

References available on request